WIDESCREEN EDITION
SHOCHIKU COMPANY, LTD.
TAIKO CHRONICLES
THE SAGA OF HIDEYOSHI
Original story by: YOSHIKAWA Eiji
Screenplay by: IDE Masato
Directed by:
OSONE Tatsuo
Hurry!
Move it up!
Push!
Push it!
Hurry!
Push!
WARRING STATES ERA
They're catching up!
Look out!
1536: YEAR OF THE MONKEY
He's crying!
The baby's crying!
We thought he'd be stillborn.
Yaemon, you have an heir!
He may look wrinkled as a prune now,
but he's a boy!
He's good.
Yaemon, congratulations!
Our rice fields may be stripped by war,
but farmer's wives are still fertile.
Onaka, thank you.
So long as we're healthy,
we'll raise a happy child.
Dear Onaka, and if our boy is healthy too,
my dream can come true.
No. I'll raise him as a farmer.
Our life may be poor but if we
work together I'll be so happy.
6 YEARS LATER
Stop, Hiyoshi!
What are you doing?
Give it back!
I'm going to be a samurai!
Enough!
Otsumi, take it from him!
Onaka, leave him.
The boy is too restless for his mother,
he has his father's blood.
I'm afraid they'll carry him off
to fight the wars when he grows.
Onaka, I'm a man without education,
that's why I'm just a burden to you.
Does your wound trouble you?
The pain is bad these days.
You should rest, darling.
How is it?
Does it hurt?
Hiyoshi, it's the day your father died,
chant the sutras from your heart.
Yes!
You boys, today I'm the general!
No, I'm the general!
Right, everyone attack me.
What?
Wait!
Look!
You decapitated Buddha!
Now that's not nice!
What's this noise?
Out of here!
Noise and more noise!
What's this here?
How did this fall?
I did it!
What? How awful!
Oh my!
Hiyoshi, Buddha will punish you for this!
It's just made of wood.
If you don't pray or believe in it, it's just wood.
It can't hurt me!
- What a disgrace!
Monk, be careful with Buddha's head.
Hiyoshi!
They say you broke the Buddha.
Idiot!
You shamed your parents!
Damned brat!
Onaka, I was shamed in front
of everybody because of Hiyoshi.
Hiyoshi, apologize to me!
Right now!
Hiyoshi!
Why don't you call me father?
Why can't you apologize?
Call me father!
Speak up, brat!
Who would pay attention to you, brat?
No appreciation!
You little brat!
All you do is take her money and drink!
That's why everybody
feels sorry for mother!
What? You little brat!
Are you talking back to me?
A brat like you had better
go and earn his own living!
If you come back you're
not staying, get it?
Smart-mouth brat!
Does it hurt?
- No.
It's so red!
It's nothing!
Hiyoshi, I'm sorry, you can't
stay here anymore, my dear.
You have to understand how things are.
Right.
Then please go and find work?
I'll speak to the landlord.
Just do it for your mother, is that all right?
Okay. I will.
I will!
Hiyoshi.
- Yes?
With this cloth, we'll make an important flag.
Careful not to drop it.
- What's a flag?
They carry it in wars.
Then it needs to be a strong color, right?
Yes.
Idiot!
Why did you put it in there?
Why don't you watch him?
Stupid!
Hiyoshi!
It seemed like good color for war.
You fool!
Marching colors are all brown!
You can't change them!
Hey, Saru!
We can't keep you here anymore.
Get lost!
But, sir?
- Shut up!
Get out!
Out of here!
Hello.
Our banner, is it ready?
Yes, it's out back.
But there's a problem.
I'll be the judge of that.
Let me see it.
Our enemies will see it clearly.
It's a fine job!
Who made this?
A small boy.
Without permission.
He's a smart lad.
I'll give him a bonus.
Where is he?
Tell you the truth, I fired him.
You fired him?
- Yes.
Are you insane?
You're a fool!
Hiyoshi.
Sister!
Why did you come home?
Mrs. Onaka, he's out of control.
He interrupts adults, talks back too
much and takes advantage of us.
When we discipline him, he makes excuses.
I can't vouch for him again,
or he'll ruin my reputation.
Did you get fired again?
Is stepfather here?
He won't come back today.
Is mother alone?
Well, go inside!
Mother?
Forgive me!
I'm not upset with you, dear.
Are you sure?
Really, you're not mad?
Mother, for the next ten
years please forget I exist.
All | want is to be a samurai.
Mother, I know you don't
want me to be a samurai,
but it's all I want.
I will be a samurai!
- Hiyoshi!
Mother, I have my father's samurai blood.
Mother, in our family my father
and grandfather were samurai.
My late father said I have samurai blood.
So I can be a samurai.
But he said don't follow him,
so I must be better than him.
I need the sword he kept in the shed.
I don't care if it's rusted, can I have it?
Please say yes, mother!
Please!
Please let me follow the samurai path!
Hiyoshi, look!
Mother, may I take it?
The sword, may 1?
Okay?
I'll take it now.
I'll carry it here.
You're not in my care anymore.
I'll be a great samurai someday.
I'll be back to get you and sister, wait and see.
I'll stay with mother forever.
I'll count on you. sister,
I'll send you all you need when you marry.
Hiyoshi.
Here is the money father set aside for my kimono...
Take it.
If I take it, you can't get married.
I won't get married until you're a samurai.
Here is mother's lucky pouch.
I see...
I'll take it.
Mother!
Hiyoshi!
Farewell, mother.
I'll be back, as a fine samurai.
First, I'll leave behind rice for you both!
Hiyoshi!
Goodbye!
Get up!
Look, I am up!
Out of my way!
- No! I
Brat!
- Brat?
You're disturbing my sleep.
How can I be in your way?
Don't talk back to me!
You little brat!
Wait!
Lad, where's your home town?
What?
When you ask, you
should identify yourself first!
He's from the Owari country.
He is Sir Hachisuka Koroku.
Hey, that's my home, too!
Where are you from?
- Me?
I'm from Nakamura village in Owari.
Wow, they're shining!
Since you're from home,
I'll let you have the boat.
Son, you forgot to tell me your name.
They call me "Saru” (Monkey)
but my real name is Hiyoshimaru.
Hey! Bring water!
Water.
Can't you carry it?
- He offered to help.
That's a horse bucket?
Yes, we just watered them.
Here, water.
And it's cool, too.
Monkey.
- Yes?
Want to work for me?
I'll think about it.
What do you want?
- I want a sword.
A sword?
I'll give you one from the shed.
I looked them all over.
They're no good.
You pulled them from the scabbards?
- Yes.
We'll have to watch you.
I want a sword like that.
That one.
That one?
- Yes.
All right. I agree.
Are you serious?
- Yes.
Hey, steal it without
getting caught within 3 days.
Right. I'll do it.
What? I said 3 days.
Right!
Shichiuchi, the boss says
you two have to pull this.
Is that so?
Hey!
Will you stop that noise!
"I'm off to find a lord to serve.
"Please save my sword
until I'm a real samurai.”
SURUGA
SAGAMI
KAI
MINO
Hiyoshi, do you remember me?
Oh, Goroji!
Hiyoshi, you left home to
become a samurai then...
But you're still...
I've searched the country to find a lord,
but I still can't find one.
I see.
Hope you find him soon.
Yes.
Pardon.
What are you doing now?
Stone merchant.
I see.
Well.
- Right.
See you!
Let's go.
OWARI: KIYOSU CASTLE TOWN
Bastard!
That's not him!
I was mistaken!
A mistaken attack on a samurai?
So you're an assassin?
No.I am...
- Silence!
Are you from Mino?
Kofu, Izu or Mikawa?
Who do you spy for?
It's a festival day.
Don't bother with him.
But?
Enough. Let him go.
Yes.
Wait!
Make sure you have the wrong man.
Take a look at my face!
And if it's no mistake,
you still won't take my head!
It's a party!
Everybody dance!
Forward!
My lord!
Stop!
Wait! Stop, you!
Please, let me see him!
My lord!
Who are you?
My lord, I'm the son of Kinoshita Yaemon,
who served with your father, Lord Nobuhide.
Kinoshita Tokichiro is my name.
I want to serve you, Lord Nobunaga.
Otherwise I will have no choice
but to stay a homeless vagabond.
You want to serve me?
Yes, I'd die for you!
What kind of skills do you have?
No special skills my lord,
but I will gladly die for
you when the time comes.
It's not fit to die for me without serving me!
Yes, but we come from the same town
and when I searched for a lord to serve,
it became my dream to serve only you!
Fine, work for me.
Thank you so much!
Hey, "Saru!"
You do resemble a monkey.
Monkey!
Go to the back and follow!
Yes, my lord!
My, it's so beautiful!
I'm sure Onaka is happy.
I can't believe Hiyoshi
gave her such fine gifts.
Onaka must be so proud of him.
He brought her so many tears as a lad.
But he was a good-natured boy.
If Chikuami was alive, he'd be so pleased.
It's so sad.
Chikuami was strict with Hiyoshi.
But Hiyoshi was a tough one.
Really, he was born nearly
half-dead and wrinkled like a prune.
Landlord, Hiyoshi sent
this letter, please read it.
Hiyoshi is now Kinoshita Tokichiro.
That sounds impressive.
"If I'm promoted and get a house,
"I will come for you.
"I don't have the samurai
lineage or social standing,
"but I will always do my best."
The lord is leaving!
Monkey, were you sitting on my slippers?
Yes, my lord.
Why?
Lord, I was warming them with my body.
With your body?
Come with me.
Yes, my lord.
"If my job is merely to
prepare the lord's slippers,
“then that is just what I'll do."
KITCHEN DEPARTMENT
KITCHEN DEPARTMENT “Lord Nobunaga
has promoted me to kitchen manager.
“Lord Nobunaga has promoted
me to kitchen manager.
"I have worked very hard.
"The result is that I have
been promoted once again."
Hey, the boss is coming!
The boss?
Monkey face?
Boss...
Go on, call me monkey face.
Don't cringe when you see me.
So call me monkey face.
If you're trying to spare charcoal, you'll
warm your face and freeze your body.
Come on, throw more coals in.
I know it's work, but ask
storage to send more coals.
Excuse me.
This boss shows great understanding.
You want us to give the
workers combat training?
They're just sitting around indoors all day,
so instead of worrying about
saving coals we'll get them outside,
practicing fighting skills.
This way we can keep them busy?
My lord, thank you for listening.
Monkey, don't you ever hold your
tongue, even with your officers?
No, lord. Sorry.
You wish to see me?
Monkey.
- Yes.
You know your job, conserving
fuel in the kitchen department?
Yes.
Someone says it's a bad idea to
leave you in charge of kitchens.
Who was that?
Maeda Inuchiyo.
I agree.
Monkey.
- Yes?
I'm taking you out of the kitchens,
and making you head of stables.
That's 30 stables, with samurai
rank and a house in town.
Thank you so much!
So, any objections?
Bad news, no objections!
Damn fool!
Inuchiyo, now it's your turn!
Yes.
RICE CAKES
Sir Kinoshita!
Sir Asano.
You're looking splendid!
Have some tea, please.
Please, sit.
This is my daughter, Nene.
Yes.
This is Kinoshita Tokichiro.
He was promoted from the kitchens,
now he's the stable manager.
Say hello.
Nene, you know Kinoshita already?
Yes.
Really?
He's written letters to me, and he sent me gifts.
That's fine, fine...
What did you say?
How could you take gifts without telling me?
I told mother.
When he sends a gift we send it back.
Sorry, sir.
Unbelievable!
I've heard you were a man to watch,
but not that you had eyes for my daughter!
I've been blind.
Nene, forget this wild man.
Matazo, take Nene back to the house!
Don't worry.
Worry?
She is dried fish in front of a cat!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Sir Kinoshita!
Sir Kinoshita, I need to ask you...
This Maeda Inuchiyo, do you know him?
I do.
Tell the truth, Sir Maeda
asked for Nene in marriage.
I agreed without asking Nene first.
When I spoke to Nene about it,
she wouldn't even answer me.
I think it's because Miss Nene
doesn't like Sir Maeda.
So I might have chosen the wrong man?
What shall I do about it now?
Maeda is a very influential man.
He's a very high-ranking samurai.
I could be in big trouble.
What if I force Nene to marry him?
Then Miss Nene will die.
Die?
Yes.
Well, let me talk to him.
You have an idea?
Sir Asano...
The least I can do is try.
I'm sure I can straighten it out.
Excuse me.
You'll talk to him?
No problem.
You'll speak to Sir Maeda?
Let me handle it.
Excuse me.
What do you want?
Say it.
Speak up!
You're fond of Asano Mataemon's
daughter, Miss Nene, right?
That's why I asked for her hand.
That's a problem.
- A problem?
Something wrong?
Nene and I have loved
each other for along time.
What? Each other?
It's true, we're also engaged to marry.
Monkey, don't joke around with me.
And if I'm telling the truth, what then?
I'll congratulate you.
Then you don't have any
objection to our marriage?
Are you serious?
- Yes, I am.
Folks are going to laugh at you.
Let them laugh.
Sir Maeda, you're sure you don't object?
Then Nene will be mine.
Monkey, are you really serious?
That's why I'm bothering you!
I knew you were an understanding man.
I feel better now.
Nene will be happy when I tell her.
So long.
It's Yamabuse Chohan!
What do you want?
Where are you going?
Shinano, Sunpu, or Imagawa?
One moment!
You're no Oda clansman, you're from Narumi!
Narumi?
Yamabuse, you bastard!
Hey, what's going on?
Sir Maeda killed Yamabuse.
What?
What will happen to Maeda?
Castle rules say the
lord must send him away.
Pardon.
Sir Maeda, is that you?
- Yes!
Please, come in.
You're getting ready to leave?
The lord was not pleased with me.
I'm giving up Miss Nene and leaving now.
Sir Inuchiyo...
I told you I was engaged to Miss Nene...
That was a lie.
I lied because Miss Nene
wasn't ready to marry.
Please accept my apologies.
Forgive me!
I've been afraid I'd never see you again.
Please, forgive me.
Please, stop that.
Truth is I was fond of Miss Nene.
But now I know who Nene really wants.
Monkey, it is you!
Don't joke with me!
If you don't believe me, go ask her.
And tell Sir Mataemon that if he lets
Miss Nene marry anyone but you...
Inuchiyo will kill him!
I came here to tell you that.
I'm not the man for Miss Nene.
Monkey, let me see you smile.
I hate to see a monkey with a sad face.
Well, take care of Miss Nene.
Understand?
Sir Inuchiyo!
Don't look so sad.
I will come back to Kiyosu again.
Bye.
Sir Kinoshita, we heard everything.
I don't know what to say.
I feel sorry for Sir Maeda.
But I guess he had to go.
Father, please let me marry Sir Kinoshita.
It's my fond wish.
Miss Nene, you wouldn't mind
having me for a husband?
No.
Sir Kinoshita, please marry my daughter!
I will.
IN MAY OF 1560, IMAGAWA YOSHIMOTO
LEFT SUNPU TO CONQUER THE ODA.
HE LED AN ARMY OF 30,000 MEN.
AFTER 13 DAYS, THEY
ARRIVED IN ODA TERRITORY.
At 4 o'clock this morning,
the Imagawa stormed into our castle!
We don't have enough men!
We can't hold out much longer!
We'll lose every man if nobody helps!
Please tell the lord!
I beg you!
Our lord is asleep.
My lord, your horse is ready!
Monkey, I will perform a Noh dance,
before you ride to battle.
Pardon my lord, then I will sing.
You're going to sing?
- Yes.
From my heart, my lord.
Good, then sing.
Be ready to die!
Prepare to fight!
Yes!
Tell me!
Our enemy, he's taken the castle!
What?!
The Imagawa have wheeled
around to the opposite direction!
Damn Yoshimoto, he'll try to attack Kiyosu next!
Monkey!
Is that you?
Monkey, how have you been?
Sir Inuchiya...
The lord waited for your return.
I see.
Monkey, let's die for our lord!
Right!
My lord!
Inuchiya, you're back?
- Yes!
Be ready to die!
Forward!
1560, MAY 19TH. ODA NOBUNAGA
DEFEATS IMAGAWA YOSHIMOTO.
Who's that?!
It's Sir Maeda.
I came back to celebrate your wedding!
I see! Thank you!
Please join us!
I'm son-in-law to this house now.
Come this way.
Everybody, come close.
Welcome!
Now join us for some saké!
Sir, he is a fine son-in-law!
Good choice!
Well, have a drink.
Thank you.
Hey! The groom, please drink.
Fine day!
Hey, it's the bride!
Aren't you lovely!
Everybody, don't we need more women?
Hey, Sir Groom, let's go!
But...
- Let's go!
Dear, take this.
You can't go home tonight!
Don't care where you go, I'm with you!
Welcome home.
I'm home.
Nene...
Yes?
I'm sorry to leave you alone tonight.
Hard to part with friends.
Forgive me.
Being here makes me happy,
I will never forget this night.
You truly feel that way?
- Yes.
Then we had better talk about something.
Nene...
Here's a gift that my mother
made with her own two hands.
She never thought of herself...
But did everything she
could to help her children.
She doesn't understand society or
manners and can't speak properly.
Nene, can you obey as daughter-in-law,
even though she is a poor villager?
Yes.
Her happiness will be my happiness.
I will respect her.
Thank you!
Now, about me, my job, my duty...
Can you enjoy sharing this life with me?
Yes.
Now I must hear your wishes.
Whatever you want in life, I'll listen.
Is it the love of a good husband?
Can you give me fine children, my darling?
Congratulations my son,
on your wedding day.
I'm so happy you'd like me to
come to Kiyosu and live with you.
But I don't wish to burden you...
Especially now that you
have realized your dreams
and you are the right hand
man to a great lord.
I'll be happy to stay here in
your home village in Nakamura
and pray every day for
your happiness to come.
Your sister Otsumi is still unmarried...
Like me she prays each day...
For your success and like me she
longs to see you again one day.
THE YEAR 1566
OWARI
SUNOMATA
To provide a foothold for the invasion of Mino
province, a castle in Sunomata had to be built.
Sakuma Nobumori led the first group of builders,
but they were utterly defeated by the Mino clan.
The second attempt by Shibata Katsuie. The
third by Oda Kageyu. Both were unsuccessful.
Lord Oda Kageyu and 90 more
were killed or injured.
Workers were drowned
or shot where they stood.
We couldn't even lay a foundation.
The land sits on a flood plain,
surrounded by enemies.
No one could possibly build a castle there!
Will no one offer me a solution?
Speak up!
I fear we'll have to forget the
idea of building a castle in Sunomata.
I agree.
I've nothing to say.
Is it impossible?!
Tokichiro!
- My lord!
Tell me what you think!
Come here!
Speak!
I hear what the retainers are saying.
But if you're afraid of water,
you can't build anything.
If you fear your enemies,
you'll never face them.
We know it's impossible,
but with brains and determination,
victory can be ours for sure.
The central problem is how we build on water,
and the strength of the soil.
We mustn't make nature our enemy.
So what is your plan?
I don't yet have a plan,
but the key is in numbers.
Numbers?
Are you asking for 5,000 men?
I don't need so many.
How many men do you need?
I'll do it with 300 men.
How many men, he says?
He'll do it with 300!
Nene, good news!
I'm going to Sunomata.
Sunomata?
Yes, Sunomata.
I leave tomorrow.
I'll have my own castle soon.
I'll be master of a castle.
Well, it hasn't been built yet
but my lord asks me to go ahead.
If 1 build it we'll bring mother to stay.
Right?
Why cry, my dear?
I know it's dangerous in Sunomata.
Many have died there, but I won't.
Don't worry!
Sir Maeda is here.
Hello.
- Hello.
What's wrong?
This Sunomata task has frightened her.
Come.
Monkey, I don't blame her.
It's a tough job you've taken.
I trust you but I'm still afraid.
Thank you.
You always take my side.
The task has beaten
higher ranking men than me.
I'll risk my life and do my best.
But if anything happens, please
take care of Nene and my mother.
Of course.
Leave it to me.
Who will you bring to Sunomata?
I have a plan.
Really?
I'll take Ronin.
- Ronin?
Yes, Hachisuka Koroku and his men.
Hachisuka? Bad idea!
He belongs to the Saito clan from Mino.
I know that.
I sent a letter last night.
Here's his reply.
But, he's refused you!
Yes, he refused.
Pardon, Nobunaga's messenger is at the gate.
Why should I see the man?
Get rid of him!
But sir, it's Hiyoshi.
"Monkey face" Hiyoshi.
You recall the kid we picked
up at the river years back?
That monkey?
Monkey?
- Yes.
How have you been?
It's been so long, more than 10 years already.
This brings back memories, such fond memories.
This stone for your slippers.
Monkey...
So you're a samurai?
Yes. As you see, with the Oda clan.
What a world this is!
I'm Kinoshita Tokichiro, on an
errand for my lord, excuse me.
Monkey!
Come back!
I won't.
I'm claiming the sword you promised me.
What?
I won't give a thing to Nobunaga's errand boy!
Get out!
You've never provided me
with a single grain of rice!
You've got nerve playing good samaritan!
Tell Nobunaga to come if he wants to talk!
You're dead wrong.
- What?
Listen to me.
It's time to give up your old Maniji flags,
and join a new alliance.
Or I can kill you!
I speak not for myself but for Lord Oda...
I speak for the warriors who have fought
nearly 100 years since the war of Onin,
praying for days of peace to come.
Words!
Sit down and listen!
You're a man who leads
2,000 vassals, aren't you?
You'd better sit down.
This man has a fine aura.
What aura?
It foretells happiness for the people.
It's good, like the Buddhist teaching.
Why don't you relax?
You can't scare him with that spear.
He's not afraid to die.
Hear him out, then decide what to do.
Please, sit.
Good. Now if you'll excuse me.
What do you want?
I'm listening.
Sir Koroku, let me ask you.
What is loyalty?
What?
You know.
But who are these Saito
that Hachisuka is loyal to?
They don't talk to you.
They fight among themselves, brother
killing brother, killing neighbors.
No one knows what to think
of them and everyone is afraid.
Sir Koroku, I'm sure you know all about it.
But you try to serve
them and still you're alone.
You think people find that admirable?
You remain loyal to these petty
souls and fail to reach for greatness.
Why not open your eyes and
see this chance to achieve it?
Sir Koroku, Oda Nobunaga
stands before your eyes!
I've been ordered to
build a castle in Sunomata,
and clear the way for the conquest of Mino.
If we miss this chance at greatness,
how can we build a better future?
I'm here now, asking you for your help.
Sir Koroku, this is my chance
to repay you for your kindness.
Let's have tea and think it over.
That samurai, did he once work for you?
I found the brat in a field.
Brat?
That's not nice.
You see a boy who worked for you.
So you can't see his virtues
and you shut your ears to his advice.
But one look shows me his success, and more...
I see that he shall rule the nation one day!
Nonsense!
Truth.
Look with your guts, not your eyes.
If you reject this messenger
today you'll regret it for 100 years!
Sir Koroku, it doesn't matter what he looks like.
What he is telling you is certainly the
truth and it's a mirror of God's teaching.
And more, his honesty and his passion...
It will make him a great
leader in years to come!
Sir Koroku, can't you see that?
Monk...
I will heed your words.
I know now...
Looking inside that he is the
better man and I will follow him.
Thank you.
Everyone!
Lord Nobunaga orders us to build this
castle in Sunomata, any way we can.
This castle belongs to none, it is
our castle and we will build it!
We'll live in this castle
for generations to come.
We've come through war after war
and hard days without hope or fortune.
But now is the time to make
a life for ourselves!
This is no one's castle but
ours, and we'll build it!
We'll build it with our own hands!
I'm all right.
Can you lift it?
Hold on.
Not too fast.
Good?
It's Gorohachi!
Hiyoshi!
Now don't cry.
If you were alive,
why didn't you come see me sooner?
I didn't want to see you until
we finished building the castle.
No need to be shy.
We're pals from the old days.
Hiyoshi, I was so happy you made general.
I not only brought my wife,
I brought 50 of my friends, too.
I see.
Keep watching us work.
We'll work hard, and we'll build this castle.
If we don't pitch in when the work is hard,
how can we hold our heads up at temple?
Damn!
Don't work too hard.
That's my wife.
Due any day.
Gorohachi, thank you.
Thank you.
Looks like the enemy is holding back.
They think Tokichiro the farmer
general is bound to be weak.
So they'll just wait until
we're nearly finished building,
then they'll mount a massive attack.
So they underestimate you.
My point exactly!
Friend Gorohachi's baby is born!
Nice healthy cries!
Hey! A baby is born!
Our baby is healthy!
Come on, get up and build the castle!
Don't let baby go hungry!
Everybody get up!
Let's feed the baby and build our castle!
Come on, let's go!
Sir Koroku!
Our victory is at hand!
Are you here because you're nervous?
We'll soon be too late.
You know the plan.
We let them work until they're
almost finished, then strike hard?
Yes, that's the plan,
but I can't bear to lose so many of our men.
What? Lose our men?
Can't you see something strange about the
way they built that wall toward the water?
Their tower, the movements of the work
and the sound of their builders, so loud.
The Oda must have hired
experts to make this incursion.
Enough.
Trust me, Heishiro, to handle these men.
Advance!
Prepare!
Charge!
Send in Monkey's messenger!
Yes, my lord!
That damned Monkey is
probably begging for more men.
What do you want?
My lord, Sir Kinoshita's work is done,
the castle has been raised.
He begs the lord come and inspect it.
He wants me to visit?
What about Mino's troops?
Sir Kinoshita fought hard
and routed all of Mino's men.
Our casualties are few and
their army was annihilated.
What?
My lord!
Monkey has done it!
Prepare my horse!
At once!
Tokichiro.
Yes?
Good work building this castle,
better work defending it.
As promised, you shall live here.
Yes, my lord.
You'll be rewarded soon.
I haven't built this
castle or defended it alone.
These many hands and
many hearts worked as one.
Everyone! I, Nobunaga thank you all!
Leader...
You hear?
Koroku.
You'll serve under Sir Tokichiro
in this castle from now on.
Monkey, you're the most
successful man in Kiyosu.
From now on you'll raise a flag
and be called Hashiba Hideyoshi.
My lord!
What a grand procession!
Who could that be?
Mother!
Tsunamata sent a messenger.
Look, over there.
Onaka!
My master Kinoshita Tokichiro
bids me to escort you.
I am Hachisuka Koroku Masakatsu.
Here she comes!
Sir, I have returned.
Thank you!
Mother, it's Hiyoshi!
Hiyoshi!
Oh my!
You look so grand!
It's been too long.
Mother!
I'm so happy to see you.
Hiyoshi...
Sister!
Nene, you must be so tired.
No, Miss Otsumi entertained me
with stories about your childhood.
Did she?
I was such a brat.
Sister...
I made your life so difficult.
Hiyoshi...
You gave me a kimono
and sash, as you promised.
Mother, come and take some rest.
No, the master of a castle shouldn't do this.
Lords have mothers, too.
What's wrong with a
boy helping his mother?
Come. Stand up.
Here.
Your mother brought these.
Have a look.
Lovely eggplants!
Don't show them to everyone.
I'm embarrassed.
A gift from your hard work?
It's the best gift I've ever received.
Thank you!
Is this your new castle?
Yes, and your home from now on.
I'm dreaming...
I swear I'm dreaming.